(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-27T00:30:29.155572",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
唸るぜ
I'm gonna roar
血泥ついたって 守りたい
Even covered in blood and mud, I want to protect you
革命道中だって 君に夢中
Even in the midst of revolution, I'm crazy about you
暗闇染み込む世界で見つけた
I found it in a world soaked in darkness
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love
甘くぬかるんだ眼差し
Your sweet, muddy gaze
変に色気あるから困った
You have a strange sexiness, so I'm troubled
手を繋ぐ勇気出したくて
I want to find the courage to hold your hand
身の程わきまえてちゃ出来ないね
If I know my place, I won't be able to do it, right?
暗いトンネルの壁 滴り落ちる秘密
From the walls of the dark tunnel, secrets dripping down
しめやかに高鳴る心
A heart solemnly throbbing fast
ダメダメ 待て待て
No, no! Wait, wait!
呪いも病も抱きしめたい
I want to embrace even the curses and illnesses.
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
Is it okay if I go wild around here?
あー 唸る戦車から ついたって守りたい
Ah, even against a roaring tank, I want to stand my ground and protect you.
革命道中だって君に夢中
Even in the midst of a revolution, I'm crazy about you.
暗闇染み込む世界で見つけた
Found in a world steeped in darkness,
センチメンタルな恋
a sentimental love.
なりふり構わず側にいたい
I want to be by your side, no matter how it looks.
不器用な君にも期待しちゃうよ
I can't help expecting things even from clumsy you.
しがらみ付けば消えそうな火に
To a flame that seems about to fade under shackles,
恋の爪立てて近づいて
I dig in my claws of love and draw near.
身を任せ抱かれて 全て失ってもいい
Surrendering myself, held close, I don't care if I lose everything.
しめやかに高鳴る心 高鳴る心
Quietly, my throbbing heart, my throbbing heart...
ダメダメ 待て待て
No, no! Wait, wait!
呪いも病も君となら
Curses and illnesses, if it's with you...
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
Is it okay if I go wild around here?
あー 泣き絶句しちゃうまで離れない
Ah, I won't let go until I'm weeping and speechless.
革命道中だって君に夢中
Even in the midst of a revolution, I'm crazy about you.
揺蕩う旅の狭間で見つけた
Found in the midst of a swaying journey,
センチメンタルな恋
a sentimental love.
突き進むなら二人で
If we forge ahead, let's do it together.
革命道中だって夢に熱中
Even in the midst of a revolution, I'm absorbed in dreams.
ダメダメ 待て待て
No, no! Wait, wait!
呪いも病も抱きしめたい
I want to embrace even the curses and illnesses.
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいよね
It's fine if I go wild around here, right?
怖くたって 唸る戦車から ついたって守りたい
Even if it's scary, against a roaring tank, I want to stand my ground and protect you.
革命道中だって君に夢中
Even in the midst of a revolution, I'm crazy about you.
暗闇染み込む世界で見つけた
Found in a world steeped in darkness,
センチメンタルな恋
a sentimental love.
いくぞー！
Let's go!
そっと 吐き出すため息を吸い込んだ
I softly breathed back in the sigh I blew out,
後悔は苦い味残して
leaving behind a bitter taste of regret.
いつも なんで？ 肝心なこと言えないまま
Why can I never say what matters most?
次の朝日が顔だしてる
As the next morning sun shows its face,
嫌になった運命を ナイフで切り刻んで
I cut up the fate I grew sick of with a knife.
もう一度やり直したら キミに出会えないかも
If I started over once again, I might never get to meet you.
僕の声が響いた瞬間に始まる
It starts the instant my voice echoes out,
命のリミット 心臓がカウントしてる
the limit of my life—my heart is counting down.
叶えても 叶えても
Even if they come true, even if they come true,
終わらない願い
these endless wishes.
汗をかいて走った 世界の秒針は
Running and sweating, the world's second hand
いつか止まった僕を置いていく
will one day leave me behind when I stop.
あと何回 キミと笑えるの？
How many more times can I laugh with you?
試してるんだ 僕を
It's testing me.
Catch the Moment
一個 幸せを数えるたびに
Every time I count a single moment of happiness,
変わっていく未来に怯えてしまうけど
I get frightened by the changing future, but
愛情の種を大切に育てよう
let me cherish and raise these seeds of love.
分厚い雲もやがて 突き破るかな
I wonder if we'll soon break through even the thick clouds.
キミの声が響いた
Your voice echoed,
僕の全身を通って 心臓のドアをノックしてる
passing through my entire body, knocking on the door of my heart.
「臆病」でも開けちゃうんだよ
Even if I'm a coward, I end up opening it
信じたいから
because I want to believe.
何もないと思ったはずの足元に
At my feet, where I thought there was nothing,
いつか深く確かな...
one day a deep, certain...
確かな根を生やす
...and growing deep, certain roots.
嵐の夜が来たとしても
Even if a stormy night comes,
揺らいだりはしない
I won't waver.
何度でも 追いついたり 追い越したり
Time and again, catching up or passing by,
キミがふいに分かんなくなって
suddenly losing sight of you,
息をしたタイミングが 合うだけで
yet just breathing in sync for a moment
嬉しくなったりして
makes me so happy.
集めた一秒を 永遠にして 行けるかな
Can we turn all those gathered seconds into eternity?
僕の声が響いた瞬間に始まる
It starts the moment my voice resounds,
命のリミット 心臓がカウントしてる
the limit of life, my heart counting down.
叶えても叶えても 終わらない願い
No matter how many wishes come true, they never end.
汗をかいて走った 世界の秒針が いつか止まった
Running till I sweat, the world's second hand one day stopped...
僕を置いていく
and left me behind.
あと何回 キミと笑えるの？
How many more times can I laugh with you?
試してるんだ 僕を
It's testing me.
Catch the Moment
逃さないよ 僕はこの瞬間を掴め
I won't let it go, I'll catch this moment!
Catch the Moment
こんばん どどどーん！
Good evening, dododonn!
お誕生日を2回迎えることになった 角巻わためです！
I'm Tsunomaki Watame, who ended up celebrating her birthday twice!
本当は6月6日が誕生日なんですけど
My birthday was actually on June 6th,
グダグダが多くて中断、そして延期になり
but due to many issues, it was interrupted and postponed,
ひゃー！角巻わため生誕祭2026 アニソンナイトフィーバー2！改めて開催させていただくことになりましたー！
Hyah! Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Festival 2026: Anison Night Fever 2 is officially happening!
迅速に動いてくださった運営さんたち
To the staff who acted so quickly,
そしてライブを見に来てくれている皆さん！本当にありがとうございます！
and to everyone watching the concert, thank you so much!
1曲目『革命デュアリズム』
The first song was "Kakumei Dualism",
2曲目『Catch the Moment』と見ていただいて分かった方もいるかもしれないんですが
and the second was "Catch the Moment". Some of you might have noticed,
前回のライブで放送した部分は、万が一のために録画を回してくださっていたので
but for the parts broadcast in the previous stream, they had recorded them just in case,
そちらの6月6日のバキバキ生誕当日のパフォーマンスを見ていただいて
so you got to see my performance recorded on my actual birthday on June 6th!
それ以外のその他MCは改めまして
As for the rest of the MC parts,
これ以上ライブ延期にならないように、今回は事前に収録をさせていただきました！
to prevent any further delays, we pre-recorded them this time!
なので、未来のリアルタイムのみんなのコメントを予知しながらMCしたいなと思いますので、いっぱいコメントしてください！
So I'll be doing this MC while predicting everyone's future comments, so please leave lots of comments!
うんうんうん、分かったよ、はい！はい！
Mm-hmm, I see, yes! Yes!
うん、あ、ありがとうねー！おめでとうもありがとう！見える、見えるぞー！
Yeah, ah, thank you! Thanks for the birthday wishes too! I can see them, I can see them!
ありがとうございます！説明はここまで！
Thank you so much! That's it for the explanation!
ここからはいつものライブ！
From here on, it's the usual live concert!
今日は生誕ライブなので、たくさんこのライブに向けて準備や練習を本当にたくさんしてきました！
Since today is my birthday concert, I've put so much time into preparing and practicing for it!
ぜひ最後まで楽しんで、そしていっぱいお祝いしてもらえると嬉しいです！
Please enjoy it until the very end, and I'd be super happy if you celebrate with me a lot!
本日のハッシュタグはー、こちら！
Today's hashtag is... this one!
6月6日と変わらず『#角巻わため生誕祭2026』になりますので、たくさんスクショとか感想とかポストしてください！
It's the same as June 6th, "#角巻わため生誕祭2026", so please post lots of screenshots and thoughts!
目指せ、またトレンド... 1位！
Aiming for trending... number one again!
後でじっとりねっとりわためも見に行きたいと思ってますので、よろしくお願いします！
Watame will be creeping around checking them out later, so please keep them coming!
では！ここまで水樹奈々さん・T.M.R.さんの『革命デュアリズム』、ソードアート・オンラインの『Catch the Moment』と歌わせていただいたんですが
So! Up until now, I sang Nana Mizuki and T.M.R.'s "Kakumei Dualism" and Sword Art Online's "Catch the Moment",
アニメや原曲MVに関連している演出を入れ込んだりしているので、みんな分かったかな？
but we incorporated stage effects referencing the anime and original MVs, so did everyone notice?
ターボわためとか、分かったかな？
Like Turbo Watame and all that, did you catch it?
ぜひ細かいところまで見てもらえると嬉しいです！
I'd be really happy if you noticed all those fine details!
ここからはゲストパートもあります！
From here on out, we have the guest segment as well!
みんなの好きなアニソンも出てくるかも？
Maybe your favorite anime song will come up too?
ということで、ゲストパート盛り上がっていきましょう！
With that said, let's get hyped for the guest segment!
割れた鏡の中 映る君の姿
In the shattered mirror reflecting your figure,
泣いている 泣いている
you are crying, crying.
細い月をなぞる指
Tracing the slender moon with your finger,
誰を呼んでいるの 消えた恋の背中
who are you calling for, turned away from a vanished love?
何度でも 何度でも 君の窓を叩くから
No matter how many times, I'll keep knocking on your window,
夜の加速度に 背中押されて
pushed forward by the acceleration of the night.
糸が切れる様に ただ、君を 君を 強く 抱いてた
Like a thread snapping, I held you, held you so tightly.
アンバランスなKissを交わして 愛に近づけよう
Exchanging an unbalanced kiss, let's draw closer to love.
君の涙も 哀しい嘘も 僕の心に 眠れ
Your tears and sad lies, let them sleep within my heart.
昨日への Merry-go-round 君を運んでゆく
Yesterday's merry-go-round carries you away.
止めたくて 止めたくて 僕は鍵を探してる
Wanting to stop it, wanting to stop it, I search for the key.
崩れ落ちそうな 空を支えて
Supporting the sky that seems about to collapse,
ひとり立ち尽くす ただ、君の 君の側に いたいよ
I stand frozen alone... I just want to be by your side.
アンバランスなKissで書かれた ふたりのシナリオ
The scenario of us two written with an unbalanced kiss.
愛と呼ぶほど 強くなくても 君のすべてが 痛い
Even if it isn't strong enough to call love, all of you hurts.
ただ、君の 君の側に いたいよ
I just want to be, want to be by your side.
アンバランスなKissを交わして 愛に近づけよう
Exchanging an unbalanced kiss, let's draw closer to love.
君の涙も 哀しい嘘も 僕の心に 眠れ
Your tears and sad lies, let them sleep within my heart.
君の心が僕を呼ぶまで 抱きしめあえる 日まで
Until your heart calls for me, until the day we can embrace each other.
長い髪なびかせて 悩ましげなボディ
Letting my long hair flutter, with an alluring body,
この都会をハイヒールで 飛び回れば Big money coming, yeah!
flying around this city in high heels, big money coming, yeah!
摩天楼の足下 時代錯誤の罠
At the foot of skyscrapers, an anachronistic trap.
血迷った 危ない奴らなら 極楽へいかせちゃうわ
If they're dangerous fools who lost their minds, I'll send them straight to paradise.
大胆な私の業の中 どれでも
Among my bold techniques, whichever one you like...
大胆な私の業のどれでも
Whichever of my daring skills it is,
スキなのをあげる
I'll give you whichever one you like.
Bye Bye Sadness. And Find out 行き場のない
Bye Bye Sadness, and find out... with nowhere to go,
あなた Ghostだから…
because you're a Ghost...
Bye Bye Sadness. And Find out 私が今
Bye Bye Sadness, and find out... right now I will
見つけ出して…
track you down...
Ghost Sweeper
吸印もいいけれど神神通力はどう？
An exorcism seal is fine, but how about divine psychokinesis?
わがままは 許さないわ
I won't tolerate selfishness.
逃がせないの Big money coming, yeah!
I won't let you escape, big money coming, yeah!
コンシャスなドレスからゴージャスなライフも
From body-conscious dresses to a gorgeous lifestyle,
いつだって 後からついてくる それが私のスタイル
it always follows after—that's my style.
クールだと誰かがいうけれど 必ず
Someone calls me cool, but I will surely
幸せをあげる
give you happiness.
Bye Bye Sadness. And Find out 行き場のない
Bye Bye Sadness, and find out... with nowhere to go,
あなた Ghostだから…
because you're a Ghost...
Bye Bye Sadness. And Find out 私が今
Bye Bye Sadness, and find out... right now I will
見つけ出して…
track you down...
Ghost Sweeper
Bye Bye Sadness. And Find out 行き場のない
Bye Bye Sadness, and find out... with nowhere to go,
あなた Ghostだから…
because you're a Ghost...
Bye Bye Sadness. And Find out 私が今
Bye Bye Sadness, and find out... right now I will
見つけ出して…
track you down...
Ghost Sweeper
魂の色は何色ですか
What color is the color of your soul?
もういっそ 折れたままで 捨てるほど 抜け出すほど 強くないよ ほら
I'm not strong enough to just give up or break away while broken, see?
もう一度 鼓動 高鳴る 何が正しいかなんて 分からないけど
Once more my heartbeat quickens, though I don't know what is right.
形のないものばかりが 大切になって行く
Only intangible things keep becoming important to me.
飾らない言葉だけが 強く結ばれてる
Only unadorned words are tied together strongly.
また躓いて 転がって それでも私だけの 魂の色は何色ですか
Stumbling and rolling again, even so, what color is my own soul's color?
ただ傷ついて 強がって それでも見つけたいよ 魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
Just getting hurt and acting tough, even so I want to find it, confirming the shape of my soul.
深海の底で一人 扉の鍵を探す
Alone at the bottom of the deep sea, searching for the key to the door.
おとぎ話はほら 泡のように全部消えて 残像だけ 次のページへ
See, the fairytale disappears like bubbles, leaving only residual images for the next page.
伸びてく枝葉が分かれて それぞれの道を派く
The extending branches and leaves separate, each taking its own path.
寂しい思い出だけが
Only lonely memories
強く根を張ってる
are strongly taking root.
また貫いて失って
Piercing through and losing again,
それでもくじけない
still, I won't lose heart.
心はどこに
Where is the heart?
器はどこに
Where is the vessel?
ただ残されて抜け落ちて
Just left behind and falling away,
それでも伝えたいよ
still, I want to convey...
魂の日々を
the days of the soul,
魂の意志を
the will of the soul.
ずっと ずっと
Forever... forever...
魂の色は
What color is the soul?
何色ですか
What color is it?
赤色ですか
Is it red?
青色ですか
Is it blue?
魂の色は
The color of the soul...
何色ですか
What color is it?
透明な過去に
In a transparent past,
不透明な明日に
in an opaque tomorrow,
生きるあなたは
you who live on,
何色ですか
what color are you?
また躓いて転がって
Stumbling and rolling again,
それでも砕けない
still, it won't shatter.
魂の色は 何色ですか
What color is the soul?
ただ傷ついて強がって
Just getting hurt and acting tough,
それでも見つけたいよ
still, I want to find it.
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
I'm confirming the shape of the soul.
ずっと ずっと ずっと ずっと
Forever, forever, forever, forever...
イエーイ！
Yeah!
3曲連続でお届けしましたが
I just sang three songs in a row...
みんな楽しんでますかー？
Is everyone having fun?
快適に見れてますかー？
Are you all watching comfortably?
『幽☆遊☆白書』の『アンバランスなKissをして』は月夜を映してもらったり
For 'Unbalance na Kiss wo Shite' from YuYu Hakusho, they showed a moonlit night,
戦闘シーンをイメージして炎に囲まれていたり
and inspired by battle scenes, I was surrounded by flames!
ダンスの振りにもね、キャラクターの技が入っていたり致しまして
And in the dance moves, characters' special moves were incorporated!
『GS美神』の『GHOST SWEEPER』にもお札をね 持っている振りが合ったり
For 'GHOST SWEEPER' from GS Mikami, there were moves like holding paper talismans,
あとは幽霊が飛んでいるそんな演出があったりしました
and stage effects like flying ghosts!
気づいたかな？
Did you notice?
そして『ソードアート・オンライン』の『ANIMA』はいつか歌いたいと思っていた曲で
And 'ANIMA' from Sword Art Online was a song I'd always wanted to sing someday,
満を持してのお披露目だったんですが、いかがだったでしょうかー？
so I finally got to showcase it. How did you like it?
いやー、カッコよかったなー
Man, that was so cool!
すごいなー、わためバキバキだなー
Amazing! Watame was totally killing it!
でも！
But...
まだこれで終わりではありません！
This isn't the end yet!
ここからは鏡・ゲートを使ったギミックや やってみたかった演出なども入ってくるので
From here on, there will be stage gimmicks using mirrors and gates, and performances I've wanted to try out,
さらに盛り上がる爆揚げステージをいっぱいやっていきたいと思います！
so I want to do lots of high-energy stages that get even more hyped up!
それでは、行ってきまーす！
Alright then, here I go!
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
Raking in the media with an invincible smile
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
Wanting to know that secret, so mysterious
抜けてるとこさえ彼女のエリア
Even her clumsy side is part of her territory
完璧で嘘つきな君は
Perfect and a liar, you are
天才的なアイドル様
a genius idol!
今日何食べた？ 好きな本は？
"What did you eat today?" "Favorite book?"
遊びに行くならどこに行くの？
"Where do you go when you go out to play?"
何も食べてない それは内緒
"Ate nothing." "That's a secret."
何を聞かれても のらりくらり
No matter what's asked, dodging questions smoothly
そう淡々と だけど燦々と
So nonchalantly, yet so brilliantly
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
Secrets seemingly visible yet unseen taste like honey
あれもないないない これもないないない
Not this either, no, no, no! Nor that, no, no, no!
好きなタイプは？ 相手は？ さあ答えて
"What's your type? Who is it? Come on, answer!"
「誰かを好きになることなんて私分からなくてさ」
"I don't really understand what falling in love is like."
嘘か本当か知り得ない
Impossible to tell whether it's a lie or the truth...
そんな言葉に
With those words,
また一人堕ちる
another person falls for you again.
また好きにさせる
Making them fall in love with you again.
誰もが目を奪われていく
Captivating everyone's gaze,
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
you are the perfect, ultimate idol.
金輪際現れない
Never to appear again,
一番星の生まれ変わり
the reincarnation of the brightest star.
その笑顔で「愛してる」で
Captivating everyone
誰も彼も虜にしていく
with that smile and saying "I love you."
その瞳が その言葉が
Those eyes, those words—
嘘でもそれは完全なアイ
even if fake, it's complete love.
はいはいあの子は特別です
Yes, yes, that girl is special.
我々は端からおまけです
We are just an extra from the start.
お星様の引き立て役Bです
Just supporting character B to make the star shine.
全てがあの子のお陰なわけない
There's no way it's all thanks to her.
しゃらくさい 妬み嫉妬なんてないわけがない
How ridiculous! As if there's no envy or jealousy.
これはネタじゃないからこそ許せない
This isn't a joke, which is why it's unforgivable.
完璧じゃない 君じゃ許せない 自分を許せない
Unforgivable if you're not perfect, I can't forgive myself!
誰よりも強い君以外は認めない
I won't acknowledge anyone except you, who is stronger than all.
誰もが信じ崇めてる
Everyone believes in and worships you,
まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
truly the strongest and invincible idol.
弱点なんて見当たらない
Not a single weakness to be found,
一番星を宿している
carrying the brightest star within.
弱いとこなんて見せちゃダメダメ
You must never show any weak spots.
知りたくないとこは見せずに
Without showing what people don't want to see,
唯一無二じゃなくちゃイヤイヤ
you must remain one and only!
それこそ本物のアイ
That is true love.
得意の笑顔で沸かすメディア
Thrilling the media with your signature smile,
隠し通すこの秘密だけは
keeping this secret hidden until the end.
愛してるって嘘で積むキャリア
Building a career on lies of "I love you,"
これこそ私なりの愛だ
this is my own form of love.
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア
Even flowing sweat is beautiful aqua,
ルビーを隠したこの眼胞
these eyelids hiding rubies.
歌い踊り舞う私はマリア
Singing and dancing, I am Maria,
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ
yes, lies are the ultimate love.
誰かに愛されたことも
Having never been loved by anyone,
誰かのこと愛したこともない
nor having ever loved anyone,
そんな私の嘘がいつか本当になること
believing that my lies will one day become true,
信じてる
I believe in it.
いつかきっと全部手に入れる
Someday I'll definitely obtain everything,
私はそう欲張りなアイドル
because I am a greedy idol like that.
等身大でみんなのこと
In a genuine, life-sized way,
ちゃんと愛したいから
because I want to love everyone properly,
今日も嘘をつくの
I tell lies again today.
この言葉がいつか本当になる日を願って
Praying for the day these words come true,
それでもまだ君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
even so, I couldn't say it to you and you,
あぁ やっと言えた
ah, I finally managed to say it.
これは絶対嘘じゃない
This is definitely not a lie...
愛してる
I love you.
あいうえお菓子した
A-I-U-E-O Sweet treats,
かきくけこんなにも
K-A-K-I-K-U-K-E so much!
さしすせソフトクリーム
S-A-S-H-I-S-U-S-E soft serve ice cream,
五臓六腑でいこう
let's enjoy it to our heart's content!
タッチついてトルテ来た
T-A-T-C-H tortes are here,
何？ヌネのり塩
N-A-N-I-N-U-N-E salted seaweed,
はっ！ヒフヘホットパイと
H-A-H-I-H-U-H-E-H-O hot pie,
みんなでぬくぬく
staying cozy together!
ショートケーキふわり
Fluffy strawberry shortcake,
キャンディーぺろぺろ
licking sweet candies.
チョコレートの川で
In a river of chocolate,
綿菓子雲見た
I saw clouds made of cotton candy.
アイスクリームと
With ice cream
プリンのお城で
in a castle of pudding,
カスタード渡狸
custard Watanuki,
二人のランデブー
our rendezvous for two!
パフェ色サンデー
Parfait-colored sundae,
あんこもハッピー
red bean paste brings happiness, too!
タイ焼きにクリーム
Cream inside taiyaki,
小悪魔ドロップ
devilish little drops.
カップケーキから
From cupcakes
苺あんみつまで
to strawberry anmitsu,
国境なきsweets
sweets without borders
仲良くなれるよ
will make us best friends!
ぼんやり夢見てごらん
Dream dreamily and look around,
キャラメルみたいにくっつこう
let's stick together like caramel!
まみむめモンブラン
M-A-M-I-M-U-M-E Mont Blanc,
やい！故ヨーグルト
Y-A-I-Y-U-Y-O yogurt,
らりるれロールケーキ
R-A-R-I-R-U-R-E-R-O roll cake,
渡狸とKissを
a kiss with Watanuki!
あいうえお菓子した
A-I-U-E-O Sweet treats,
かきくけこんなにも
K-A-K-I-K-U-K-E so much!
さしすせソフトクリーム
S-A-S-H-I-S-U-S-E soft serve ice cream,
五臓六腑でいこう
let's enjoy it to our heart's content!
のんびり早弁
Relaxed early lunch,
焼きのりあぶって
toasting dried seaweed,
おにぎりコロコロ
rolling rice balls around,
友達ほかほか
warm friends together!
紅葉まんじゅうと
Maple leaf manju and
あんぱんお月さま
moon-shaped anpan,
渡狸に始まり
starting with Watanuki,
渡狸に終わる日々
days ending with Watanuki.
ほんのり見つめてごらん
Take a gentle look,
甘くて苦い夕焼けを
at the sweet and bitter sunset.
タッチついてトルテ来た
T-A-T-C-H tortes are here,
何？ヌネのり塩
N-A-N-I-N-U-N-E salted seaweed,
はっ！ヒフヘホットパイと
H-A-H-I-H-U-H-E-H-O hot pie,
みんなでぬくぬく
staying cozy together!
まみむめモンブラン
M-A-M-I-M-U-M-E Mont Blanc,
やい！故ヨーグルト
Y-A-I-Y-U-Y-O yogurt,
らりるれロールケーキ
R-A-R-I-R-U-R-E-R-O roll cake!
ミルフィーユ ワッフル ボンボン
Mille-feuille, waffle, bonbon,
ムース 渡狸 パイ
mousse, Watanuki, pie,
シュークリーム バナナゼリー
cream puff, banana jelly,
ババロア 渡狸
bavarois, Watanuki,
ホットケーキ バームクーヘン
pancakes, baumkuchen,
渡狸 ワタヌキ
Watanuki, Watanuki,
バター 渡狸 クレープ
butter, Watanuki, crepe,
ワタヌキ ワタヌキ
Watanuki, Watanuki.
ワタヌキとごはん
Meals with Watanuki,
ワタヌキとおやつ
snacks with Watanuki,
ワタヌキと肉まん
meat buns with Watanuki,
ワタヌキと北京ダック
Peking duck with Watanuki.
みつまめ 渡狸
Mitsumame, Watanuki,
渡狸 シロップ
Watanuki syrup,
全時 ワタヌキ
Watanuki all the time,
大盛り 渡狸 丼
large serving of Watanuki bowl.
こんがり 思い出 色
My memories are colored well-done.
ハチミツ みたい に とろける
Melting like honey...
あいうえ お菓子 した
A-I-U-E, I've had some sweets!
かきくけ こんなにも
K-A-K-I-K-U-K-E, so much like this!
さしすせ ソフトクリーム
S-A-S-I-S-U-S-E, soft serve ice cream!
五臓六腑で いこう
Let's go with every fiber of our body!
たちつて トルテ 切った
T-A-C-H-I-T-S-U-T-E, I cut the torte!
なにぬね のり塩
N-A-N-I-N-U-N-E, salted nori flavor!
はひふへ ホットパイ と
H-A-H-I-H-U-H-E, with hot pie!
ふたりで ぬくぬく
Keeping warm together!
まみむめ モンブラン
M-A-M-I-M-U-M-E, Mont Blanc!
やいゆえ ヨーグルト
Y-A-Y-I-Y-U-Y-E, yogurt!
らりるれ ロールケーキ
R-A-R-I-R-U-R-E, roll cake!
渡狸 と KISS を
A kiss for Watanuki!
ワタヌキの 甘みと
Watanuki's sweetness and
ワタヌキの 苦み
Watanuki's bitterness
ワタヌキの 酸味で
and Watanuki's sourness...
好き 好き ラブ・コンボ
Love love, love combo!
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Japari Park!
今日もしドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Rocking and rolling today, too!
うー！がぉー！
Woo! Roar!
高らかに笑い笑えばフレンズ
If we laugh out loud, we're Friends!
喧嘩して すっちゃかめっちゃかしても仲良し
Even if we fight and make a big mess, we're still best friends!
けものは居ても のけものは居ない
There are wild animals, but no outcasts here!
本当の愛はここにある
True love is right here!
ほら 君も手をつないで大冒険
Come on, hold hands and let's go on a great adventure!
(ワン・ツー・スリー)
(One, two, three!)
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Rocking and rolling today, too!
姿かたちも十人十色 だから魅かれ合うの
Everyone has a unique form, that's why we draw each other in!
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら
When our fingers gently touch against the sunset sky,
はじめまして
nice to meet you.
君をもっと知りたいな
I want to get to know you better.
うー！がぉー！
Woo! Roar!
振り向けば あちらこちらでトラブル
Turn around and there's trouble everywhere!
なんてこった てんでんバラバラ ちんぷんかんぷん まとまらない
Oh dear, everyone's scattered, totally clueless, completely untamed!
けものですもの 大目に見てね
We're wild animals after all, so please go easy on us!
みんな自由に行きている
Everyone lives freely!
そう 君も飾らなくたって大丈夫
Yeah, you don't need to put on an act either, it's okay!
(はい どうぞ)
(Here you go!)
Nice to meet you ジャパリパーク！
Nice to meet you, Japari Park!
今日からはどうぞよろしくね
Please treat us well starting today!
いつでもいつまでも優しい笑顔 君を待っていたの
Always, forever, with a gentle smile, we've been waiting for you!
開かれた扉 夢をいっぱい語ったら
Once the doors open and we share all our dreams,
どこまでも続いてくグレートジャーニー
a great journey unfolds as far as the eye can see!
東へ吠えろ 西へ吠えろ
Howl to the east! Howl to the west!
世界中に響けサファリメロディ
Let the safari melody resonate around the world!
―Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Japari Park!
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Rocking and rolling today, too!
姿かたちも十人十色 だから魅かれ合うの
Everyone has a unique form, that's why we draw each other in!
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら
When our fingers gently touch against the sunset sky,
はじめまして
nice to meet you.
君をもっと知りたいな
I want to get to know you better.
うー！がぉー！
Woo! Roar!
ララララ ララララ Oh Welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
La la la la, la la la la, Oh welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ ラララララ 集まれ友達
La la la la, la la la la, gather around, friends!
ララララ ララララ Oh Welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
La la la la, la la la la, Oh welcome to the Japari Park!
ラララ...
La la la...
素敵な旅だち
A wonderful journey
ようこそジャパリパークへ！
Welcome to Japari Park!
Fire! Fire! Oh-oh-oh-oh!
Fire! Fire! Fire! Oh-oh-oh-oh!
Night of Fire!
Welcome to the broken low
Welcome to the famous disco night
Come on lady, come and go
Come on lady, get me once and right
Not a danger, not a blacky stranger
Rock it, rock it, knock to my door
I'll open, speak my name now, speak it if you know how
Fly to me, get ready for the
Night of fire, you better better stay
You better better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire, come over over me
Come over over the top, you've never been here
Night of fire, you better better stay
You better better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire, come over over me
Come over over the top, you'll have a night of fire
You'll have a night of fire
Welcome to my rocky show
Welcome to the fire of the night
Come on baby, let it go
Come on baby, let me stick you tight
Not a danger, not a blacky stranger
Rock it, rock it, knock to my door
I'll open, speak my name now, speak it if you know how
Fly to me, get ready for the
Night of fire, you better better stay
You better better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire, come over over me
Come over over the top, you've never been here
Night of fire, you better better stay
You better better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire, come over over me
Come over over the top, you'll have a night of fire
You'll have a night of fire
You better better stay
The prayer to play
Come over over me
You've never been here
Night of fire
You'll better better begin
Come over over the top
You'll have a night of fire
Rock it, rock it
Welcome to the broken low
Welcome to the famous disco night
Come on lady, come and go
Come on lady, get me once and right
Not a danger
Not a blacky stranger
Rock it!
Knock to my door
I'll open, speak me name now
I'll open, speak my name now
Speak it if you know how
Fly to me, get ready for then
Night of fire
You'll have a Night of Fire!
Night of Fire!
ということで！
And with that!
ここまでたくさんの 本当たくさんのゲストさん達と
Up until now, with so many—really, so many guests—
歌って踊ってきましたが、いかがだったでしょうかー？
we've been singing and dancing! How did you like it?
楽しんでますかー？
Are you enjoying yourselves?
なかなかね、こんなにホロメンが集まることってないので
It's rare for so many Hololive members to gather like this,
もう本当生誕祭お祭りにって感じで嬉しいです！
so I'm really happy for this festive birthday celebration!
ゲストさん達にも大きな拍手をー！
Give a big round of applause to our guests, too!
いや、ありがとうみんな！
Ah, thank you, everyone!
ゲストのみんな、ありがとう！
Thank you to all our guests!
いや、このね、鏡の...
So, you know, this...
モニターから登場するという演出をやってみたいなぁと思って
I wanted to try a stage effect where everyone appears from mirror monitors,
『アイドル』と『スウィートパレード』で実現していただきましたー！
and they made it happen during "Idol" and "Sweet Parade"!
あの、わためいと...
Um, Watamate,
スバルさん、エルフレさん、
Subaru-san, Elfriend-san,
3人たちがペンライトを振ってくれてたのも可愛かったし
the three of them waving penlights was super cute, too!
やっぱりホロメンって可愛いよなぁ！
As expected, Holo members are just so cute!
あと、『ようこそジャパリパークへ』では
Also, in "Welcome to Japari Park",
サバンナで肉食動物たちに囲まれて
surrounded by carnivores in the savanna,
虎のような人間がいたような気もしますが
I felt like there was even a human tiger-like figure in there,
みんながね、仲良くなっていく様子を表現させていただきましたー！
but we portrayed everyone becoming good friends!
まぁちょっとね、最後みんなの表情怪しかったけどね
Well, everyone's expressions at the end were a bit suspicious, though!
そして！『Night of Fire』！
And then, "Night of Fire"!
これはこちら、英語の得意なEN・IDメンバーのみんなと一緒に歌いたいと思って
I wanted to sing this with the EN and ID members who are so good at English,
横に立って歌っても浮かないように英語頑張ったんだけど
and I tried my best with English so I wouldn't stand out badly next to them...
大丈夫だったかな？
Was it okay?
海外アニキ〜？
Overseas bros~?
「英語上手」
"Your English is good"
ってコメントが来てると思う！
I'm sure comments like that are coming in!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
でも！
But!
みんなもっと気になるところがあったかなと思うんですが
I think there were some things you were even more curious about...
あ、車ね？
Ah, the car, right?
攻めてたね！
That was bold!
あとはパラパラ踊るギリ割るロボね
And the Giriwaru robot dancing Para Para!
やりたい放題させていただいて、とっても楽しかったです！
We got to do whatever we wanted, and it was so much fun!
でも！まだ終わりじゃない！
But! We're not done yet!
ちょっと着替えてくるので、待っててくださーい！
I'm going to go change, so please wait for me!
はーい！
Okay~!
よいしょ、よいしょ... 着替えて、着替えて... ふぅ...
Heave-ho, heave-ho... changing, changing... whew...
はーい！
Alright!
あ、もう着替え終わった！
Ah, I'm already done changing!
さて！
Now then!
次の曲なんですが...
As for the next song...
なんと！
Believe it or not...
なんかみんなもう知ってそうだけど
Although I feel like you all know already...
次の曲は新曲！
The next song is a brand-new song!
『灰色の証明』をやります！
I'll be performing "Haiiro no Shoumei"!
わためチャンネルにてMV公開中なので
The MV is out right now on the Watame Channel,
MVもぜひ見てくださーい！
so please go check out the MV as well!
そして楽曲リリースもしているので
And the song is also officially released,
「いいな」と思ったらぜひ買ってください！
so if you like it, please be sure to buy it!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you so much!
では！
Now then!
新曲『灰色の証明』
The new song, "Haiiro no Shoumei",
魂込めて歌います！
I'll sing it with all my soul!
聴いてください
Please listen.
灰色の証明
[Proof of Gray]
静寂に包まれた ゼロ地点の感情
Sentiments at ground zero, wrapped in silence.
期待を背負っているのは 私ではないから
Since I'm not the one carrying expectations,
主人公はいつだって 輝いている誰かで
the protagonist is always someone who shines bright,
見上げるだけじゃ 何も変わらない
and just looking up changes nothing.
今この時だけの
Exclusive to this exact moment,
瞬間的な優位性で 駆け抜けて
I sprint through with momentary superiority!
灰色の空 裂いて "私"の全てを
Tearing through the gray sky with all that I am,
"運命の物語"に 叩きつけて 打ち砕け
I slam against the scenario of fate and smash it to pieces!
自信は微塵もない あるのは渇望だけ
Without a shred of confidence, driven solely by desire,
ただ自分の生命を 証明しよう
I will simply prove my own existence,
"此処"にいた事を 刻むように
as if to engrave the fact that I was right here!
綺麗な勝ち方は望むべくもない
I can't even dream of a clean win,
華やかさも必要ない
nor do I need any glamour.
それが私だから
Because that's who I am.
歴史はいつだって勝者が作るモノ
History is always made by the victors,
だけど記憶はその限りじゃない
but memories aren't bound by that.
今この時だけは
Only for this moment,
決断的な刹那性に飛び込んでいけ
plunge right into this decisive, fleeting second.
灰色で描く“私”の思いが
My feelings, painted in shades of gray,
美しき痛みをも乗り越えて書き換えてく
overcome even beautiful pain, rewriting everything.
後悔は1ミリもない
I don't have a single regret.
あるのは灼熱だけ
There is only scorching heat,
ただ自分の生命を蹴り上げるように
as if kicking my very life into high gear.
始まりは些細 最早どうだっていい
The beginning was trivial, and it doesn't matter anymore.
突き動かされ指先を伸ばす
Driven forward, I reach out with my fingertips.
現実は残酷だと気付いていないわけじゃない
It's not that I don't realize reality is cruel.
諦めるその時は“今”ではなかったらしい
It seems the time to give up was not "now."
灰色の空高くもう一度点火して
Igniting once more high into the gray sky,
ただ自分の生命を証明しよう
I will simply prove my existence,
そこにいた事を刻むように
as if engraving the fact that I was here.
It's a second chance, new answer
声を張れ Realize
raise your voice and realize.
I can't change the past forever
私の Future is one way slide
my future is a one-way slide.
はい！
All right!
ということで新曲「灰色の証明」！
So that was my new song, "Proof of Gray"!
やったー！披露できたー！
Yay! I finally performed it!
やっと証明できたー！
I finally proved it!
聴いてくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for listening!
この楽曲は岸田教団&THE明星ロケッツの皆さんに制作していただきまして
This song was created for me by Kishida Kyoudan & THE Akeboshi Rockets,
スポーツだったり みんなが頑張りたい時に
and I wanted to create a cheer song that could give people strength in sports,
力になれるような応援ソングを作りたいと思い
or whenever they want to give it their all,
色々語ったらかなり熱くてカッコいい楽曲に仕上がりました！
and after talking it through, it turned into a super passionate and cool song!
上手くいかないことがあっても また立ち上がって前に進む
Even when things don't go well, you get back up and move forward.
わためにとっても背中を押してくれる そんな特別な楽曲に今回のライブになりました！
Through this live show, it became a really special song that pushes Watame forward too!
みんなにとってもそうだったら嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if it does the same for all of you!
こちらの新曲MVいっぱい見て 楽曲もぜひ購入して
I'd be super happy if you watch the new MV a lot, buy the song,
わための音楽を応援していただけたらとっても嬉しいです！
and support Watame's music!
目指せ！武道館ライブ！
Aiming for a Budokan live concert!
と、あ、ここでまだ告知していないものが一つありまして
And, ah, there's one more announcement I haven't made yet...
ライブじゃないんですけど…
It's not a live show, but...
なんと！
Believe it or not!
ドドーン！
Ta-da!
『角巻わためのHave a nice day』書籍刊行決定ー！
"Tsunomaki Watame's Have a Nice Day" is getting a book release!
ということで『ハバナイ』が本になります！
So "HabaNice" is officially becoming a book!
出版社は『かいけつゾロリ』や『おしりたんてい』などで有名なポプラ社様より
Published by Poplar Publishing, famous for "Kaiketsu Zorori" and "Butt Detective",
オリジナルグッズ付きで12月に刊行予定です！
it's scheduled for release in December with original merch!
まだ少し先にはなりますが 楽しみに待っててもらえると嬉しいです！
It's still a little ways off, but I hope you look forward to it!
そして…ドドーン！
And... ta-da!
今年も角巻わため誕生日記念グッズが受注受付中です！
Pre-orders for Tsunomaki Watame's Birthday Celebration Merch 2026 are open again this year!
ラインナップを改めて紹介させてください！
Allow me to introduce the lineup once more!
ドド・ド・ド・ド・ドーン！
Ta-da-da-da-da-da!
ふみママ描き下ろしの「わためのあったかブランケット」！
First is "Watame's Warm Blanket", illustrated by Fumi-mama!
なんと！セクシーです！
It's actually pretty sexy!
そして裏面にはわためいとが居ます！
And on the back, there's a Watamate!
丸めるとね わためいとの形になりますので2WAYでも使えます！
If you roll it up, it takes the shape of a Watamate, so it can be used in two ways!
ぜひ温もりを感じてください！
Please feel its warmth!
そして…ドド・ド・ド・ドーン！
And... ta-da-da-da!
「わため＆わためいと温感マグカップ」！
"Watame & Watamate Color-Changing Mug"!
こちらはモタ先生に描き下ろしていただきまして
This one was illustrated by Mota-sensei!
最初は夜の風景なんですけど
At first, it shows a night scene...
温かいものを入れていただくとその熱を感知して 朝の景色に柄が変わるような仕様になっております！
but when you pour a warm drink in, it detects the heat and changes into a morning scene!
わための配信を意識してデザインしてもらったので
It was designed with Watame's streams in mind,
配信を見ながらぜひ温かい飲み物を飲んでくださいね！
so please enjoy a warm drink while watching my streams!
そして まだあります！
And that's not all!
ドド・ド・ド・ド・ド・ド・ド・ド・ドーン！
Ta-da-da-da-da-da-da-da!
「わためいとクッション」！
"Watamate Cushion"!
クッションとして使うもよし 飾るもよし
Great as a cushion, great for display!
とってもかわいいクッションなので ぜひ...
It's super cute, so please put it in your room...
...に置いてみてください！
...please try putting it in!
最後に！
And lastly!
ドドド... ドン！
Drumroll... Bam!
来たー！ わためなりきりアイマスク！
Here it is! Watame dress-up eye mask!
眠っている顔と...
The sleeping face and...
わためと言えば、これ！
Speaking of Watame, this!
の、表情にしていただきましたー！
...expression, they made it into this design!
果たして需要はあるのか？
Is there actually any demand for this?
気になる方はぜひ、なりきりアイマスク手に入れてください！
If you're interested, please get your dress-up eye mask!
こちらのグッズをフルセットで購入していただいた方には...
For those who purchase these goods as a full set...
ドドド... ドン！
Drumroll... Bam!
わための直筆サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカードと
Watame's handwritten signed postcard with a message and...
角巻わためのショートボイスセット15種類が特典として付いてきます！
a set of 15 Tsunomaki Watame short voice packs as a bonus!
今年も無制限で直筆を書かせていただく予定なので
I plan to write signatures without limit again this year,
ぜひこの機会にゲットしてみてください！
so please take this opportunity to get it!
ということで、新曲MV公開中！
So with that, the new song MV is out now!
楽曲リリース中！
The song is now released!
誕生日グッズ発売中！
Birthday goods are on sale!
12月カバーない書籍刊行決定！
Publication of a coverless book in December is confirmed!
よろしくお願いいたします！
Thank you so much!
この後は10時15分からメン限アンコールライブもありますので
After this, at 10:15, there's a members-only encore live,
よかったら、あっ間違えた、メンバーに入っていただいて
so if you like... ah, wait, please join as a member and
引き続いて楽しみましょう！
let's continue to enjoy it!
今年はなんと2days！お誕生日たくさんお祝いしてくれて、ありがとう！
This year was amazingly 2 days! Thank you for celebrating my birthday so much!
めちゃくちゃ嬉しかったです！
I was super happy!
それでは、メン限アンコールライブで会いましょう！
Well then, see you at the members-only encore live!
またねー！
See you!
フレー フレー フレー fever fever
Hurrah, hurrah, hurrah, fever fever!
描いていこう（yeah!） 花びらいっぱいのステージを
Let's paint (yeah!) a stage filled with flower petals!
fever fever 叶えていこう（fever!）
Fever fever, let's make it come true (fever!)
ほらまた目覚める bloomy cue!
Look, awakening once again, bloomy cue!
並行世界をぎゅっとねじ曲げ（hey! 行こう!）
Twisting parallel worlds tightly (hey! Let's go!)
きっと出会えた今なんだ ベストな世界線に（hey!） いるんだよ？ ciao!
Surely we met now, on the best world line (hey!), right? Ciao!
“夢”と“あいまいな目標”ってどう違う？
How are "dreams" and "vague goals" different?
（you got this, ねぇ goddess） 掘ろっか答え探し
(You got this, hey goddess) Shall we dig to find the answer?
わくわくしたら夢なんだ 大丈夫信じて
If it gets you excited, it's a dream! Don't worry, believe in it!
贈り合いましょう（yeah!） 吼えるようなエールを（yeah!）
Let's send each other (yeah!) roaring cheers! (yeah!)
響かせよう 君の中疼いてる
Let's make it echo! The aching inside you,
咲きたい蕾たちへ合図を（yeah!）
give the signal to the buds waiting to bloom (yeah!)
いっせいに送るよ（yeah!） ひらけ！と
sending it all at once (yeah!), saying "Open up!"
また一つみつけた 君と出会えたことの意味を
Found another one: the meaning of meeting you!
フレー フレー フレー fever fever
Hurrah, hurrah, hurrah, fever fever!
描いていこう（yeah!） 花びらいっぱいのステージを
Let's paint (yeah!) a stage filled with flower petals!
fever fever 叶えていこう（fever!）
Fever fever, let's make it come true (fever!)
ほらまた目覚める bloomy cue!
Look, awakening once again, bloomy cue!
everybody, go for it! 内なるモンスター
Everybody, go for it! The monster within,
閉じ込めた背中のファスナー ちゃんと堪えた
zipped up on your back—you endured it well!
ガマン強い君が master 内なる diva を信じてね forever
Patient as you are, you're the master! Believe in your inner diva forever!
踊ろうよ dreamer 時の神のご自慢の（hey!）
Let's dance, dreamer! The God of Time's proud (hey!)
文字盤を盗んじゃおう いたずらで未来は進化する
clock face—let's steal it! The future evolves through mischief!
大丈夫信じて最強の今を
It's alright, believe in the ultimate present!
まるで宇宙の果ての停留所？ 君の声で星降るイリュージョン！
Like a bus stop at the edge of space? A starry illusion with your voice!
君へこのエールを（君へこのエールを）
Sending this cheer to you (sending this cheer to you)
君へこのビートを（君へこのビートを）
Sending this beat to you (sending this beat to you)
君とだからある歌を（君とだからある歌を）
This song that exists because of you (because of you)
届けてくんだ（こっちも贈るよ） ずっとずっと
We'll deliver it (I'll send it too), forever and ever!
贈り合いましょう（yeah!） 吼えるようなエールを（yeah!）
Let's send each other (yeah!) roaring cheers! (yeah!)
響かせよう 君の中疼いてる
Let's make it echo! The aching inside you,
咲きたい蕾たちへ合図を（yeah!）
give the signal to the buds waiting to bloom (yeah!)
いっせいに送るよ（yeah!） ひらけ！と
sending it all at once (yeah!), saying "Open up!"
また一つみつけた 君と出会えたことの意味を
Found another one: the meaning of meeting you!
フレー フレー フレー fever fever
Hurrah, hurrah, hurrah, fever fever!
描いていこう（yeah!） 花びらいっぱいのステージを
Let's paint (yeah!) a stage filled with flower petals!
fever fever 叶えていこう（fever!）
Fever fever, let's make it come true (fever!)
ほらまた目覚める bloomy cue!
Look, awakening once again, bloomy cue!
これからも夢に向かって一緒に歩いて行こうね！
Let's keep walking together toward our dreams!
全然ありえないようなことが
Even things that seem completely impossible
突然起きたり
suddenly happen,
攻略法をください…
please give me a guide...
時代はいつも過渡期だ
The era is always in a transitional period.
必然ぶった正解に意味を求めていちゃ疲れちゃう
Seeking meaning in answers that pretend to be inevitable will just tire you out.
冗談混じりくらいが心地がいいもんだ
A bit of joking around is comfortable.
くだらないことで笑って
Laughing at trivial things,
目を見てちゃんと話がしたい
I want to look into your eyes and talk properly.
なんせ僕ら人間だ！
After all, we are human!
間違いくらいあるのでしょう
Mistakes are bound to happen.
「Q. 目に見えないもの見ようとする度
"Q. Every time you try to see the invisible,
遠ざかってくの なんだ？」
what moves further away?"
なぞなぞばっかの世界で
In a world full of riddles,
君に何を問いかけよう？
what should I ask you?
そのアイデアが、そのユーモアが
That idea, that humor,
僕らを照らすヒントになる
will become a hint that illuminates us.
why do you think? 何故に思う？
Why do you think? Why do you think?
この辺境な惑星で！
On this remote planet!
君が抱いてたその不思議を
The mysteries you've been holding,
解き明かしにゆこう
let's go and unravel them.
La-la-la-la, la-la-la-la-la